# **BISWAJEET JENA**

#### FRONT-END DEVELOPER



**+**44 07776630167



biswajeetjena921@gmail.com



X KT2 6RZ, London

PORTFOLIO: HTTPS://LUXURY-CARAMEL-439AE7.NETLIFY.APP

### **FXPFRTISF**

- Hands-on Java Script, React.JS, Next.JS, Angular.JS, Express.JS, freemarker.
- Python, R, Matplotlib, Seaborn.
- · Firebase, SQL, Git Hub, Git Bash, Jira, Google Cloud, AWS.
- · Debugging, project management, Data analytics.
- Google Analytics, Machine learning, AI, data visualisation.
- Product development, seo.
- · Hands-on React.JS, Redux and Routing, with expertise in hooks and state, forms and Form validation.
- Working knowledge of C, C++, and Java.
- Bug Fixing and Testing on own before deployment.
- Microsoft ASP.NET MVC and web development with their implementation.
- · Strong ethics in maintaining the code flow and good communication for easy bug handlings.

# OTHER SKILLS

- THE ABILITY TO ANALYZE COMPLEX TECHNICAL INFORMATION.
- CAN ANALYZE, DESIGN AND IMPLEMENT DATABASE STRUCTURES.
- DETAIL ORIENTED.
- EXCELLENT PROBLEM SOLVER.
- EXCELLENT WITH GIT, GITHUB, SOURCETREE AND FIREBASE.
- QUICK LEARNER AND ALWAYS KEEN TOWARDS ADDING MORE TECH STACKS.

## **PROFILE**

I'm a software engineer that comes with the package of being a quick learner which helps in learning new tech stacks and implementing them quite quickly. I tend to quickly adapt and perform as per the conditions. I also have a photographic memory which again helps me maintain a good flow in the code and quality control. Apart from that I come with a lot of tech stacks that relate to the field of Data science like Python, Matplotlib, Machine learning and its applications, etc. Professional and dedicated to learning new tech stacks every day to build up good foundational knowledge. I believe I could not only design, code and create new pages and apps but also can provide expertise in data marketing analysis and revising websites accordingly to ensure user satisfaction. Can generate statistical reports of sales and how the targets can be more achievable by using and implementing my data scientist tech stacks.

### EXPERIENCE

#### ALIPPO, HSR LAYOUT, BANGALORE

#### **Principle Software Engineer**

#### 2020-2021

It was my start-up that dealt with E-commercing on a wholesale level. The whole point was to introduce a business model similar to Alibaba.com in India. I was the Principle software engineer dealing with front-end and also parts of back-end with the use of Java Script. Majorly handled CSR. The implementation of Freemarker to establish data mappings and a tool as a template that can be used a connector.

#### **PRISTYN CARE**

#### **Software Engineer-1**

#### 2021-2022

- Designing templates and making them live.
- Quality Control on all the builds and passing commits.
- Designing and coding Forms and Pagination of data from databases.
- Server-side rendering using Next.JS
- Client-side rendering using React.JS
- Using React to create new React Apps and make them live.
- Data mapping using freemarker.
- Directs software design and development.
- Evaluates interface between hardware and software.
- Advises customers regarding maintenance of software system.

### EDUCATION

#### SECONDARY SCHOOL

Sacred Heart School

2003 - 2016

#### **BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY**

SRM University

**B.Tech in Computer Science** 

2016 - 2020

#### **MASTERS DATA SCIENECE**

Kingston University

2022 - 2023

# PROJECTS

PORTFOLIO: HTTPS://LUXURY-CARAMEL-439AE7.NETLIFY.APP

SPOTIFY: https://luminous-gecko-

e85d2e.netlify.app

SORTING VISUALIZER :

HTTPS://GILDED-PASCA-

9741F8.NETLIFY.APP

ECOMMERCE: https://verdant-froyo-

fe26a0.netlify.app

ADMIN DASHBOARD: https://frabjous-

crisp-5ee258.netlify.app

**CANDY CRUSH:** 

HTTPS://TANGERINE-

PALMIER-DE827F.NETLIFY.APP

- BUILDING WEB PAGES FROM SCRATCH AND ADDING VARIOUS FUNCTIONALITIES LIKE
- REACT-SELECT AND INTEGRATING WITH FIREBASE.
- CREATED A DOCTOR-UPLOADER PAGE USING REACT JS AND REACT NATIVE.
- CREATED A LEAD PAGE CMS DASHBOARD WHICH IS LIVE AND RUNNING.
- CREATED MANY OTHER PROJECTS USING VARIOUS RANGE OF LANGUAGES LIKE JS.
- VANILLA JS, NEXT JS, REDUX, PYTHON FOR WEB ENGAGE.

# MASTERS DATA SCIENCE RESEARCH KINGSTON UNIVERSTY

2022 - 2023

- Worked on a time series analogy using a machine learning project.
- Worked on Crime detection using Matplotlib and a data science project.
- Major dissertation on traffic signs prediction using machine learning and also traffic management and various factors affecting them.
- Worked on python and R in various fields and gained expertise.
- Learn implementation of databases and Jupiter notebook.